MATIN ADEBAYO

Phone: +44 7867436755 | Email: madeayo04@gmail.com | United Kingdom

GitHub: github.com/matinayo Website: matinayo.netlify.app

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/matin-adebayo/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution-oriented .NET Software Developer with experience designing and implementing scalable, secure solutions and web application development for complex systems across diverse industries. Possess working knowledge in web services technologies, microservice architecture, and development of Service-Oriented Applications (SOA) based on Rest APIs using Microsoft .NET Framework.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Microsoft.NET
- Angular, React
- C#
- Blazor
- Google Flutter

- JavaScript, AJAX, jQuery, TypeScript
- SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Oracle, MongoDB
- Virtual Reality and Game Development with Unity

- Cloud Services Microsoft Azure
- Docker
- Azure DevOps
- Azure CI/CD Pipelines
- Unit Testing

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Microsoft 2023

Credential: https://learn.microsoft.com/en-gb/users/abdulmatinadebayo-7788/credentials/c3b18cdf67ecc92c

• The Three Pillars of Effective Communication

LinkedIn 2023

Credential: https://www.linkedin.com/learning/certificates/efbf211651d5dbc4cd52abf58cbbb16056e8cb3b1eb6e2ea69ec08d72eba377a

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Avrion - Hertfordshire, UK

.NET Developer

Jan 2024 - Present

- Developed and maintained Sales CRM web applications with .NET and Angular, leveraging a range of Azure services including Azure Functions, Azure B2C, and other cloud solutions to enhance scalability and performance.
- Integrated Maximizer and Sage CRM to develop custom quoting tools, streamlining sales processes and improving client engagement.
- Implemented a centralized login and administrative system using Azure B2C with impersonation for administrative functions, enabling secure user authentication and flexible user flows while allowing administrators to access user accounts for support purposes.

 The tools used in the development of this project are:

 NET 0. A product SOL Companies of Azura Cit.
 - .NET 8, Angular, TypeScript, SQL Server, Microsoft Azure, Git.
- Collaborated with clients and stakeholders to gather requirements, align on project goals, and provide regular updates.
- Wrote and executed unit and integration tests to ensure code quality, reliability, and maintainability.

Novacept - London, UK

Junior .NET Developer

Nov 2022 - Dec 2023

- Built and maintained an innovative Property Management Solution (Powered by Artificial Intelligence) using Blazor and API
 technologies. The solution offers homeowners and tenants an intuitive online software platform for managing property services,
 including tenant information management, payment processing, generation of financial reports, and more.
 - The tools used in the development of this project are:
 - .NET 7, Blazor, JavaScript, SQL Server, Docker, Microsoft Azure, Git.
- Designed and developed a comprehensive talent life cycle platform, encompassing the entire Hire-to-Retire process. This platform
 efficiently manages candidates, partners, clients, hiring managers, account managers, and recruiters. Through worldwide sourcing
 capabilities and optimized resource allocation, this solution empowers organizations in effective talent management.
 The tools used in the development of this project are:
 - .NET 7, Blazor, JavaScript, SQL Server, Docker, Microsoft Azure, Git.

- Engaged in comprehensive system study and proficient in database engineering tasks, including the creation of databases, tables, intricate stored procedures, and SQL Performance Tuning. These efforts have significantly improved data manipulation capabilities and ensure enhanced consistency.
- Experience with dependency injection containers, applying S.O.L.I.D design principles, and developing applications within an Azure environment.

Triversa Solutions Limited Feb 2021 - Nov 2022

Junior .NET Developer

Developed a financial and Anti-Money Laundering (AML) reporting enterprise application for government cooperation and banking
institutions. This project was built using microservice architecture leveraging tools including Azure Service Bus, SQL Server, Docker.
It consisted of three services (the core AML application used to flag suspicious transactions, the AML reporting solution used to
report transactions in various format including JSON, XML, and Excel, and an ETL application used for extracting and managing
customer data).

The tools used in the development of this project are:

.NET 5, and later updated to .NET 6, JavaScript, SQL Server, Oracle, Docker, Microsoft Azure, Git.

Developed and provided support in the development of a Failed Bank Management System. A Deposit Insurance Solution for the
Nigeria Deposit Insurance Corporation (NDIC), that enhances quick resolution of failed banks by paying all stakeholders (Depositors,
Creditors, and Shareholders) from funds recovered for failed banks from Loan Recoveries, Sales of bank-owned Physical Assets and
Investments, and collateral sales from judgement enforcement.

The tools used in the development of this project are:

.NET v4.7, JavaScript, Telerik reporting, SQL Server, IIS, Git.

- Responsible for designing and developing an ETL process to efficiently handle a large volume of customer data.
- Optimized performance and scalability of intricate SQL stored procedures through thorough tuning efforts.

SAED Integrated Services May 2020 - Jan 2021

Backend Developer (Intern)

- Developed a Data Cleansing platform to sensitize the demographic and biodata of citizens based on created set of rules.
- Developed cross-platform mobile applications with Google Flutter, incorporating top-notch design principles to meet and exceed customer requirements.
- Integrate third-party APIs and collaborated with backend engineers to define and implement RESTful API services with ASP.NET Core.
- Built an easily consumable API based on S.O.L.I.D design principles.
- Supported the organization's testing model, ensuring that backend components and client solutions adhered to requirements and delivered reliability.

The tools used in the development of this project are:

Google Flutter, .NET Core (Web API, Worker Service), SQL Server, Azure DevOps, Git.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Information Technology – First Class Honours
 Middlesex University, London

2022 - 2023

Relevant Modules: Artificial Intelligence, Web-based Mobile Applications, Novel Interaction

 Advanced Diploma in Software Engineering (ADSE) – Distinction Aptech World Wide

2019 - 2020

CompTIA A+ Certification

Aptech World Wide 2019